SHAHELA

Hyderabad, India 500048 I 7993142855 I shahela487@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Ambitious person seeking to deepen knowledge of IT Management, Networking by completing independent research projects focused on Cybersecurity. Experienced in using IoT and Cloud Computing and in-depth understanding of correct procedures. Skilled in mastering data and study related procedures and protocols to ensure service excellence. Well-versed in project management and research planning. Pursuing new professional challenges and offering key abilities with 4 years of experience.

SKILLS

- Research protocols
- Project management
- Microsoft office, Excel
- Organizational skills
- Supervision & leadership

EXPERIENCE

07/2023 - Current

Associate Consultant Sustainable Living Lab - Chennai, India

- Actively engaged in pioneering research and development initiatives within the dynamic landscape of emerging technologies, with a primary focus on areas such as Cybersecurity, Artificial Intelligence (AI), and Generative AI.
- My role encompasses a multifaceted approach, involving both research and practical application in the form of content development and project management.
- Stayed abreast of industry trends, emerging tools, and best practices to ensure the integration of the latest advancements into project development.

05/2021 - 05/2023

Research Fellow Centre for Advanced Systems, DRDO — Hyderabad, India

- Designed and implemented an automated Internet of Things model for server monitoring.
- Worked on Cyber threat modelling methods and Google Dorking, Cybersecurity incident management.
- Managed application security vulnerabilities.

- Add improvements to our current processes.
- Developed analytic skills and attention for detail by analyzing system logs and identifying potential issues.
- Responsible for day-to-day operations and administration of the IT infrastructure.
- Worked on computer vision with OpenCV and developed a face recognition system.
- Worked on machine learning algorithms to implement a phishing detection model.
- Elaborated Microsoft management console commands for Windows 10
- Research on internal cloud implementation.
- Knowledge of Blockchain technology.
- Knowledge of Quantum cryptography.
- Coordinated with development teams to build office automation applications.
- Provided technical support for ISO ISMS 27001:2013 audit in the organization.

01/2021 - 12/2021

Business Development Executive

Ability Quiver Private Limited - Delhi, India

- Contributed to the technical recruiting of the MNC's
- Communicating with top MNC for technical hiring requirements

09/2019 - 12/2020

Embedded Engineer

Sree Embedded Technologies — Hyderabad, India

- Researched latest technologies to determine effectiveness in solving specific issues.
- Lead project of software systems engineers and internal and outsourced development partners to produce reliable solutions for complex systems.
- Contributed technical skills to support new product development and existing product maintenance.

04/2018 - 08/2019

Sales Associate

Squadstack - Noida, India

- Remote work involving client deals for product sales
- Training the employees

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

10/2015 **M.Tech**: VLSI

JNTU, Hyderabad — Hyderabad

06/2013 B.Tech: Electronics & Communication Engineering

JNTU, **Hyderabad** — Hyderabad

LANGUAGES

English: First Language Hindi: Advanced Telugu: Proficient Arabic: Beginner

German: Beginner

CERTIFICATIONS

- Completed Government officials training program on IoT by NIELIT, CDAC. (Certificate no-FSPrime/IoTl279).
- Attended Online Short-Term Course on Cryptography, Forensics, and Cyber Security: Recent Trends & Technologies by National Institute of Technology Warangal & Manipal Institute of Technology Bengaluru.
- Completed online course on CISSP-Certified Information Systems Security Professional.
- Mastering CVSS v3.1 a course of study offered by FIRST.org.
- Completed MATLAB onramp certificate.
- Attended ISO 27001 Lead Auditor certification by Udemy.
- Completed Block chain Developer Training.
- Certified in **Generative AI** courses by Coursera nad Google Cloud.
- Certified in Career Essentials in Generative AI by Microsoft and LinkedIn.
- Certified in **ChatGPT for Everyone** by Guvi, Google for Education Partner.
- Completed **Prompt Engineering** course by Deep Learning Al.
- Completed Intellectual Property Awareness Training by Intellectual Property Office, India.

PUBLICATIONS

- Published a paper on Implementation of ISO 27001: 2013 ISMS in a Defence Lab: A Case Study in International journal of Advances in Engineering and Management (IJAEM) ISSN: 2395-5252.
- Published a paper on Application of low cost loT device for precise monitoring of Temperature and Humidity of Server Rack in Data Center in Sciforum, MDPI-MOL2NET 22, Switzerland, Published: 29 May 2022.

- Published a paper on Implementation of secure private cloud infrastructure in JETIR (Journal of Emerging Technologies and Innovative Research). (ISSN:2349-5162),in JETIR July 2022, Volume 9, Issue 7.
- Published a paper on Implementation of Cyber Defense Tools for Safeguarding IT Assets in Xplore journal of ISME, at 11th International Conference on Contemporary Issues in Management (CIM23) Bengaluru.
- Presented a paper on Recognising Phishing URLs using Ensemble Approach for Sustainable Cyber Usage in International Conference on Sustainable Development Goals -Opportunities, Challenges and Future at St, Joseph's College, Hyderabad.
- Published a paper on Exploring the Performance nad Accuracy of Digital Twin Models in IRJET, May 2023.
- Published a paper on Quantifying e-waste Generation and Management: An Empirical Analysis in IRJET, May 2023

PERSONAL DETAILS

Father's Name: Mohammed Sadiq Marital Status: Married

Birthday: April 05, 1992 Nationality: India

Gender: Female

DECLARATION

I, SHAHELA, hereby declare that the information contained herein is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Shahela Hyderabad, Telangana